A Guide to the Rockwell International, Collins General Aviation Division Publications, 1979-1984
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Rockwell International, Collins General Aviation Division Publications, 1979-1984
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms1994-012
0.2 Cubic Feet; 1 box
Twenty-one booklets from the Collins General Aviation Division of Rockwell International contain information regarding products of the division, such as Electronic Flight Instrument system and Weather Radar systems. One booklet is from Dorne & Margolin, Inc., about their antennas and accessories.
Rockwell International
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
The Rockwell International, Collins General Aviation Division Publications were donated to Special Collections in March and May 1994.
Appraisal
Duplicates were deaccessioned.
Biographical/Historical Note
The North American Rockwell Corporation formed in 1967 by the merger of North American Aviation, Inc., founded as a holding company for a number of aviation companies in 1928, with the Rockwell-Standard Corporation, founded in 1919 by Colonel Willard Rockwell. The company became Rockwell International in 1973, when it also acquired Collins Radio Co., founded in 1933 by Arthur Collins. The company made the rocket engines for Saturn V and several Space Shuttle orbiters for NASA.
In 1996, Boeing purchased the defence and aerospace divisions of Rockwell, and in 2001, the conglomerate separated into Rockwell Collins and Rockwell Automation.
Source:
Editors of Encyclopaedia Britannica. "Rockwell International Corporation." Encyclopedia Britannica. Published May 20, 2015. https://www.britannica.com/topic/Rockwell-International-Corporation. Accessed February 13, 2020.
Braband, Ken C. The First 50 Years: A History of Collins Radio Company and the Collins Divisions of Rockwell International. Cedar Rapids, Iowa: Communications Department, Avionics Group, Rockwell International, 1983.
"In Brief: Rockwell to Change Name to Rockwell Automation after Rockwell Collins spinoff." Military and Aerospace Electronics. Published April 1, 2001. https://www.militaryaerospace.com/communications/article/16710689/in-brief. Accessed February 13, 2020.
Scope and Content
Twenty-one booklets from the Collins General Aviation Division of Rockwell International contain information regarding products of the division, such as Electronic Flight Instrument system and Weather Radar systems. One booklet is from Dorne & Margolin, Inc., about their antennas and accessories.
Arrangement
This collection is organized by type.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Separated Materials
The First 50 Years: A History of Collins Radio Company and the Collins Divisions of Rockwell International by Ken C. Braband was seperated to the Rare Books Collection.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Archives of American Aerospace Exploration (AAAE); Aeronautics; Brochures; Pamphlets; Science and Technology
Contents List
- Rockwell International, Collins General Aviation Division, Pilot's Guides, 1975-1980
  - Collins 718U-5( ) Lightweight HF Airborne Transceiver pilot's guide, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Collins ANS-31C Area Navigation System pilot's guide, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Collins FIS-84 Flight Instrument System pilot's guide, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Collins FDS-85 Flight Director System pilot's guide, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Collins WXR-220 Weather Radar System pilot's guide, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Collins LRN-85/85A/85T Long Range Navigation System (3rd Edition) pilot's guide, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Collins WXR-200A Weather Radar System, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Collins LRN-70/80 Long Range Navigation System pilot's guide, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Rockwell International: Collins Commercial Avionics System Information, undated
  - Collins Flight Profile Advisory- Pro Line FPA-80, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Collins AP-106A Autopilot Pro Line flight control for turboprops, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Collins FMS-4050/4100 Flight Management Systems, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Collins Pro Line 4 Avionics System, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Collins Pro Line 4 Avionics System Canadair Regional Jet, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Collins Pro Line 4 Avionics System Falcon 2000, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Collins Pro Line Radios, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Collins Pro Line II Digital Avionics System, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Collins Commercial Avionics, Partners On A Journey of Innovation, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Collins TCAS II Traffic Alert and Collision Avoidance System, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Collins TWR-850 Turbulence Weather Radar System, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Right On The Numbers, The Canadiar Regional Jet, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Rockwell International, Collins General Aviation Division, Self-Test Guide, undated
  - BITS mode self-test guide, Collins EFIS-85A-2a Electronic Flight Instrument System, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Dorne & Margolin, INC., 1993
  - Dorne & Margolin, INC., Aviation Antennas and Accessories, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 4)